《銀時:あれは
自ら ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを取り込んで！
Is she taking the Stand into her own body?
But you're just His Excellency!
って… ただの閣下だろうが！》
(お岩)ﾌﾞヮﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
お前も蝋人形にしてやろうか？
I'll turn you into a wax dummy, too!
D-Don't underestimate me, you old hag!
なめんな このｸｿばばあ！
♪♪～
ｵﾗ ｵﾗ ｵﾗ ｵﾗ ｵﾗ…！
It's providence that a dead person goes to the next world.
死んだﾔﾂは
あの世にいくのが 自然の摂理？
(お岩)あぁ そうさ そのとおりさ｡
Yes, that's right! But not everyone can go to heaven.
だが 落ちる水がすべて
盆に収まるとは かぎらない｡
Some people can't go there!
どうしても こぼれ落ちちまう
ﾔﾂらだって いるんだ！
This is the only place for people like them!
ここは そんな行き場のない
亡者たちの唯一の居場所なんだ！
ｱﾝﾀに… ｱﾝﾀに それを奪う
権利なんか ありゃしないんだよ｡
You... You have no right to take it from them!
盆からこぼれ落ちてんのは
ﾔﾂらなんかじゃねえ…｡
What keeps them here is not their failure to go to heaven.
Okami, it's because of you!
女将… ﾃﾒｴだ！
《ﾊﾞ… ﾊﾞｶな！
No way!
まさか これは… これは！》
It can't be.
This is... This is...
ﾌﾞヮﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
この薄汚い くさればばあが！
You old, dirty hag!
お前も 糖人形にしてやろうか？
I'll make sugar candy out of you!
[Tou (Sugar)]
[Be Very Careful When Using Ghost Stories]
ﾌﾞヮﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ！ 薄汚いばばあが！
You dirty, old hag!
お前も糖人形にしてやろうか？
I'll make sugar candy out of you, too!
《閣下だと!? ﾊﾞｶな！
His Excellency?! Impossible... he can transform into His Excellency and yet still be himself?!
ﾔﾂも 閣下化して
なお 自我を保てると!?
ん!? いや それ以前に
いったい 誰を憑依…｡
Wait! More importantly, who...
ﾚｲ!? あっ！ しまった!!
did he possess himself with? Rei!
Damn!
ここは ﾚｲを
閉じ込めておいた呪縛房！》
This is the spell prison I trapped Rei inside of!
Okami.
(ﾚｲ)女将 旦那…
いつから 私たちは➡
Danna... How long has it been like this?
こんなことに
なってしまったんだい？
(ﾚｲ)私たちは… この旅館は➡
Us... this inn... when we started
始まりは もっと
ｽﾃｷなところだったじゃないか｡
it was a much more wonderful place.
((お岩:来るかい？
どうせ 身寄りもないんだろう？
Do you want to come with me? I'm sure you don't have any relatives to go to.
(お岩)いいかい？ この宿はね
盆から こぼれた水を➡
Listen, this inn is for ghosts who failed to get to heaven.
元の盆に戻してやるのが
役目なんだよ｡
極楽にはいけなかった連中だが➡
They couldn't make it to paradise,
せめて 極楽の湯で
成仏させてやろうじゃないのさ))
but we can at least give them a bath here and help them get to heaven.
(ﾚｲ)そうして
ここで たくさんの魂が➡
So many souls have been able to go to heaven from here.
天に還っていった｡
ここは行き場を失った魂を 最後に
見送ってあげる 終着駅だった｡
This place was like a terminal for lost and weary souls who had no other place to go.
However, after that day,
それが あの日を境に
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞたちが ふきだまる➡
the inn now lies in ruins filled with Stands.
今のような よどんだ廃墟に
成り変わってしまった｡
女将も旦那も
本当は 気づいてるんだろう？
Okami and Danna, both of you knew about this, didn't you?
ﾌﾝ！ 小娘が よけいなことを
ﾍﾞﾗﾍﾞﾗと やかましいわ｡
Stop blathering, little girl. The Stands are our business partners. That's all!
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞは 私たちの商売相手
それだけさね！
ｷﾞﾝ｡
あぁ｡
Gin.
All right.
(ﾚｲ)長年にわたり 霊たちを
この地に縛り続けてきた➡
The time has come to break these cursed chains that have tied down the sprits here for so long.
呪われた鎖を
解き放つときが来たんだ｡
(ﾚｲ)ｷﾞﾝ… すべてを
解放してやっておくれ｡
Gin, please free them all.
The Stands... and...
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞたちを… そして 女将を！
Okami.
Don't think you can push your luck just because you have become His Excellency!
閣下になった程度で
調子にのるな!!
ﾚｲ程度の ｻﾞｺを
憑依させたところで➡
You think you can beat my husband just by possessing a small fry like Rei?!
ｳﾁの旦那に勝てる と
思ってるのかい!?
ぐっ… うわぁぁ！
ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ…！
Such a weak vessel. I'll smash it!
こんな細い体
へし折ってくれるわ！
Second Stand! Iron Girl!
ｾｶﾝﾄﾞｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ ｱｲｱﾝｶﾞｰﾙ！
[Kami (God)]
ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ… ん!?
♪♪～
ぎゃぁぁぁ!!
《お岩:急激に力を増大させた！
まさかこれは… これは！》
He's suddenly increased his power. Don't tell me this is...
This is...
(神楽)ﾌﾞ
ﾊﾊﾊｰｯ！
お前を 薬局にあるｳﾝｹﾙの➡
I'll turn you into a figure like that cardboard
あの ちょっと古いﾀﾓさんの
ﾊﾟﾈﾙ人形に してやろうかぁ!!
Yunkeru standup of Tamori at the pharmacy!
ｶﾞﾊｯ…!!
Did he switch to another Stand?! Has this guy got multiple Stands?!
《ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを 切り替えただと!?
この男 ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを複数
憑依させていたというのか!?》
ほぉぉぉ… とおぁぁっ!!
《お岩:なんという力…｡
What amazing power!
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを 同時に数体操るなど
私でも 10年かかったぞ！
It took ten years even for me to handle a couple of Stands at the same time!
I'm losing energy. I must replenish quickly!
消耗が激しい…
早く 回復せねば！》
Third Stand! Cabaret Club Smile!
ｻｰﾄﾞｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ ｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗｽﾏｲﾙ！
[Tae]
(お妙)ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ… お弁当の時間に
してやろうかぁ!!
It's time for lunch!
That is... Dark Matter!
《お岩:あれは… ﾀﾞｰｸﾏﾀｰ！
She distorted space to create dark matter within her hands!
空間を歪ませ暗黒物質を
己が手に生み出したぁぁ!!》
はぁっ… 卵焼きだぁぁ!!
Fried eggs!
ぐわぁぁ… 焼けるぅぅ…!!
It burns!
ぐうぅぅ…！
とどめをくれてやる！
It's the final blow!
Go! Fourth Stand! Jimmy Heavenly!
いけぇぇ ﾌｫｰｽｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ ｼﾞﾐｰﾍﾌﾞﾝﾘｰ!!
♪♪～
[Shin (New)]
[Niku (Meat)]
I turned into some kinda freak! Who is this?!
知らない人 出たぁぁぁ!!
誰だ ｺﾚ!?
こんなﾔﾂ 入れた覚えねえぞ！
I don't remember inhaling anyone like this!
What kind of imitation hero is this? What kind of meat-puppet is this?!
なんだ この まがいもん！
何 肉ﾏﾝ!?
ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ… よほどｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを
寄せ集める体質らしい｡
You must be very good at collecting Stands!
雑霊が 次々と ついていくわ！
Evil spirits are gathering around you!
ばばあ ﾃﾒｴの仕業か!?
適当に ﾋｮｲﾋｮｲ入れてんのは!?
Old hag, are you putting in these Stands randomly?
(新八)ぐあっ 銀さん満員です！
Gin, it's full in here!
おい～ どっから出てんだ ﾃﾒｴは！
Hey! Just where do you think you're coming out of?!
It hurts!
ぐるしいっ!!
神楽!?
Kagura! What the? Where did you just come out from?!
それ どこ どこから出てきたの!?
ぐわぁっ!!
Gin! Look in front! Front!
銀さん 前 前！
お前しか 見えねえ!!
All I can see is you!
口説き文句とかじゃなく!!
Don't get me wrong. I'm not trying to flirt with you.
ぶほぉぉっ!!
(みんな)うぅっ！
くっ… や やばい！
Shoot! All the Stands have left him!
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞが全部
飛び出しちゃったよ！
Gin! Run away! You don't have any Stands!
(神楽)銀ちゃん 逃げろ！
生身ｱﾙ！
ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ… もう遅い！
うらぁぁぁ!!
It's too late!
No, I have one left.
《いや まだ ひとりいる…｡
It's a chance I have to take!
ｲﾁかﾊﾞﾁかだっ!!》
死ねぇぇぇ!!
Die!
てやぁぁぁ…!!
♪♪～
[Sen (Missionary)]
(銃声)
A completely unrelated character took her out!
どうでもいいﾔﾂが 倒したぁぁぁ!!
♪♪～
うっ うぅ…｡
まさか…
あれだけの数のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを➡
I can't believe it! You can handle so many Stands at the same time.
同時に使いこなすとは
みごとだよ｡
Splendid.
ｷﾞﾝ それに ｱﾝﾀらも…｡
Gin...and all of you.
さすがは
あの お登勢が➡
No wonder Otose sent you guys.
送り込んできた
ﾔﾂらなだけはあるね｡
こいつぁ 私の負けかねぇ ｱﾝﾀ｡
It looks like I've lost. Oh, dear.
(TAGOSAKU)ｵﾚが… 護る｡
えっ!?
I'll...protect you.
約束だ…｡
I promised...
(TAGOSAKU)大切な すべてを…｡
important... things.
((旦那:す… すまねえな お岩｡
I...I'm sorry...Oiwa.
(お岩)いいよ
もう しゃべらないで｡
It's all right. Stop talking.
(旦那)だ… 大丈夫だ｡
Don't worry.
(旦那)何も変わらないよ｡
ｱﾝﾀ…｡
Everything will be the same.
Dear...
ずっと ｵﾚは… そばにいる｡
I'll...be with you forever.
(旦那)約束だ…))
I...promise.
(すすり泣く声)
(TAGOSAKU)ｵﾚが… 護る！
I'll...protect you.
約束したろ…
ｵﾚが護ると言ったはずだ｡
I promised you.
I said I would protect you.
お岩 お前も この宿も
ｵﾚが護ると言ったはずだ！
Oiwa...You...this inn... I said I would protect both! I, Tagosaku, promised!
このTAGOSAKUがぁ！
よしな もう勝負は…！
Stop, the fight is over!
(幽霊たち)女将を護れ…
ｵﾚたちの宿を護れ…｡
Protect Okami. Protect our inn.
ｱﾝﾀら…！
Protect Okami.
You guys!
Wh-What the-!
こ… これは！
Protect our inn.
客や従業員 ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞたちが…！
The customers, employees and Stands are all...
going to Tagosaku!
TAGOSAKUに集まっていく！
いや 宿のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞだけじゃない｡
No, it's not just the Stands at the inn.
あれは…！
That's...
(ﾚｲ)この里中の生物のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞが➡
Tagosaku sucking in all the Stands from every living thing in the village!
TAGOSAKUによって
吸い取られていく！
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを吸い取る!?
それって 死…｡
He's sucking in all of the Stands?! That means... death.
(ﾚｲ)恐れていたことが
ついに起こってしまったね｡
Our fears have finally come to pass.
ｱﾝﾀ！ こりゃ 何のﾏﾈだい!?
Dear!
What are you doing?!
この宿は… ｵﾚが護る！
This inn...I'll protect it!
お岩 みんなのｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを集めれば
客 いっぱい…｡
Oiwa, if I collect everyone's Stands, all these customers,
お岩 もう寂しくない！
Oiwa, you won't feel lonely anymore.
ｱﾝﾀ 何を…!?
Dear, what are you talking about?
(お岩)この里中の生き物のｽﾀﾝﾄﾞを
抜き取っちまおうってのかい!?
Are you going to take the Stands of all the living creatures in this village?!
そんなﾏﾈしたら 残された肉体は➡
If you do that,
the bodies will rot, and everything in this village will die.
やがて腐り この里の生物は
死に絶えちまうよ！
Stop it! Can't you hear me?!
やめるんだ！
私の声が聞こえないのかい！
TAGOSAKU！
Tagosaku!
うお～っ！
くっ… ﾀﾞﾒだ！
女将の言うことすら聞かない！
It's no good! He won't even listen to Okami.
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞの暴走だ！
The Stand has gone out of control!
(ﾚｲ)これだけたくさんのｽﾀﾝﾄﾞが
一つのところに長くとどまれば➡
Keeping so many Stands in one place for a long time
負の情念がふきだまり 増大して➡
will increase the negative emotions
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞの力も
外界に影響を及ぼすまでになる｡
and the power of the Stands will have an even bigger influence on this world.
もはや人間の力では
抑えられないまでに…｡
To the point where they can't be controlled by human power.
♪♪～
(ﾚｲ)ここは もう自然の理から
外れた魔界｡
This place will no longer be a province of nature, but a living hell.
暴走を止めねば
負の情念は増大し続け➡
The negative emotions will continue increasing
魔界は この世界を
侵食し始めるよ｡
and the entire world will erode if we don't bring this under control.
そんな！ ｱﾝﾀが
そんなことを… ああっ！
No! You can't be doing such a thing!
ｷｬ～ｯ！
Rei!
(お岩)ﾚｲ！
うっ… ううっ！
うわ～っ！
ﾎﾞｸらまで取り込もうとしてる！
He's trying to take us, too!
すべてを… すべての魂を
飲み込もうとしてるのか！
He's going to suck up every soul!
新ちゃん しっかりつかまって！
うわ～っ！
Shin-chan! Hang on tight!
おい！ ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞのﾃﾒｴらが あれに
飲み込まれたら ｼﾒｴだぞ！
Hey! If you Stands get swallowed up by him, it's all over!
一旦 ｵﾚの体の中に避難するんだ！
Escape into my body for now!
早く！ こっちだ！
銀ちゃん！
Hurry up, this way!
Gin!
ぐっ… あと ちょっとだ｡
Almost there...
あと少し… あっ！
Just a little...
ｷﾞｬｰｯ！ 銀さんのｽﾀﾝﾄﾞまで
飛び出してきた!!
Even Gin's Stand came out!
What the hell are you doing, you wavy-haired jerk!
(お妙)何さらしてんだ 天ﾊﾟｰ！
吸い込む力が半端ねえ！
His suction is unbelievable! Every household should have at least one.
一家に一台 欲しいくらいだ！
全員 ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞになっちゃいましたよ！
Everyone has become Stands!
早く 身体に戻っ…｡
Hurry! Return to my body.
What the hell?! That weirdo just made off with your body!
ちょっと！ なんか変なのが➡
勝手に身体
持ってっちゃいましたよ！
Xavier, wait! That's my body!
ｻﾞﾋﾞｴﾙ 待て！ それｵﾚの身体!!
おい 返せ ﾊｹﾞ！
Hey, give it back, baldy! Oh crap! My body has been stolen!
最悪だ 空き巣にやられた！
こっちだよ！
This way!
私の身体に入りな！
早くつかまって 早く！
Enter my body! Take my hand!
Hurry!
って つかまれるか～！
No way!
どっから手 差し伸べてんだ
ばばあ！
You old bat, where do you think you're showing your hand from!
そんな穴から入るくらいなら
魂 消し飛ぶほうがﾏｼだ！
I would rather lose my soul than go in there!
しかたないね じゃあ前から｡
ばばあ！ 殺すよ ﾎﾝﾄ殺すよ！
Fine, already. Then how about the front?
You're dead, you old bat! Seriously!
(TAGOSAKU)
お岩 みんな ひとつになるんだ｡
Oiwa, everyone will become one.
みんな肉体を捨てて ひとつに…｡
Everyone will throw away their bodies and become one.
そうすれば みんな ずっと一緒｡
Then everyone will be together.
さびしいことなんて何もない！
You won't feel lonely anymore.
うわぁ～っ！
ばばあ！
Old hag!
Gin!
銀さん！
(お岩)ﾚｲ！
Rei!
(みんな)うぅっ！
(お岩)ﾚｲ！
Rei!
女将は １人じゃないよ｡
Okami, you're not alone.
みんな みんな
女将の心のなかに…｡
Everyone!
You carry all our souls within your heart.
(お岩)なんて…
なんてことだよ まったく｡
Oh, my God. I can't believe this.
私は あの子らに
謝らなきゃならない｡
I must apologize to them.
私は どうやら あの子らに➡
I seem to have forced them into terrible penance.
とんでもない苦行を
強いていたようだよ｡
あの子らを
地上に縛りつけていたのは➡
It was neither their wounds, nor regret that kept them in this world.
未練でも癒えぬ傷でも
なんでもない｡
この私だったんだ｡
It was me.
(お岩)初めて あの子らを見たのは
母を病で亡くしたとき➡
The first time I saw those kids was back when illness took my mother.
泣きじゃくる私の前に
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞは現れた｡
I was crying really hard when the Stand appeared before me.
思えば あの子らは➡
Looking back, now I remember that they always appeared when I was alone.
決まって私が１人のときに
姿を見せた｡
いつの間にか私の隣にいて➡
Soon after, they were next to me, and sometimes would encourage me.
時に私を励まし
時に一緒に泣いてくれた｡
Sometimes we cried together.
いつしか私の隣には
人間ではなく➡
It became more natural to be with Stands than with other humans.
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞがいることが
当たり前になっていた｡
私にしか見えない友人たち｡
Friends that only I could see.
私は選ばれた人間なんだと
思っていた｡
I thought that I was chosen.
これは天が私に大事を為せと
授けてくれた能力なのだと…｡
That it was a power granted to me by the heavens to carry out some important deed.
この宿はね 盆からこぼれた水を➡
This inn is for ghosts who failed to get to go to heaven.
元の盆に戻してやるのが
役目なんだよ｡
極楽には行けなかった連中だが➡
They were not able to go to paradise,
せめて極楽の湯で
成仏させてやろうじゃないのさ｡
but we can at least give them a bath here and help them get to heaven.
そして私は
たくさんの魂を天に還した｡
I helped a lot of souls go to heaven.
笑顔で成仏していく彼らを見て
私も満足していたはずだった…｡
It was satisfying watching them smile before passing away.
だが旦那を亡くしたとき
私は気づいてしまったんだよ｡
However, when my husband passed, I realized something.
私の隣には いつの間にかｽﾀﾝﾄﾞしか
いなくなっていたことに…｡
That the only beings next to me were... all Stands.
私は もうずっと前から
１人だったということに｡
That I...have been alone for a long time.
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞたちを失えば
私は ﾎﾝﾄに１人になってしまう｡
I'd be really lonely if I lost all the Stands.
そう思うと
たまらぬほど怖かった｡
And the thought of it made me extremely scared.
あの子らは そんな私の弱い心を
知っていたんだね｡
They probably understood my weak feelings.
ずっと前から…｡
From so long ago...
そう 初めて会った
そのときから ずっと｡
Yes, from the very first time I met them.
ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞ使いだって？
笑わせるじゃないかい｡
Me, a Stand user?
Give me a break!
Save souls who've lost their place to go?
行き場を失った魂を救う？
思い上がりも はなはだしいよ｡
Stop being so presumptuous!
救われていたのは 私…｡
I was the one being saved.
あの子らは ずっと昔から
私を支えてくれていたんだ｡
For the longest time, they've been keeping me company.
１人ぼっちの私を
心配して➡
They were worried...about me being all alone.
あんな姿になってまで
ずっと…｡
Even when they turned into ghosts... Always...
そう ずっと
私のそばにいてくれたんだ｡
Yes. They always stayed with me.
ごめんよ
すまなかったね みんな｡
Sorry. I'm really sorry, all of you.
今まで ありがとよ｡
Thank you for everything.
うおぉ～!!
あっ！
あれは！
取り込まれていた ｽﾀﾝﾄﾞたちが➡
That's it!
The inhaled Stands are going to heaven!
成仏していく！
(幽霊たち)女将｡
Okami!
(幽霊たち)
女将は １人じゃないよ｡
Okami, you're not alone...all of us...
みんな みんな
女将の心の中に➡
...we will always be...in your heart.
ずっと ずっと 一緒にいるよ｡
We will always...always be with you.
(TAGOSAKU)約束だ お岩｡
I promise...Oiwa.
♪♪～
私にできることは
これしかないんでね｡
This is all I know how to do.
また ｶﾞｲｺﾂの背中 流してやるさ｡
I'll just start scrubbing down the backs of skeletons again.
１人で 宿を
切り盛りしてくってんですか｡
Are you going to manage the inn all by yourself?
１人じゃないさ
みんな ここにいるよ｡
I'm not alone anymore.
I have everyone in here now.
今度こそ ﾔﾂらを救う仕事ってのが
してみたいのさ｡
I want to save them this time. I'm repaying a favor.
恩返すためにもね｡
ｱﾝﾀらも 成仏できないときには
また 遊びにきな｡
If you can't get to heaven, come back here again. I'll send you to heaven right away!
一発で昇天させてやるよ｡
ｹｯ ばばあに
背中 流してもらうなんざ➡
Having that old hag wash my back doesn't sound very good!
御免こうむるぜ｡
大丈夫ですかね 女将さん｡
I wonder if Okami is all right.
She looks kind of sad.
なんだか 寂しそう｡
ﾌﾝ 寂しくなんかねえよ｡
I think she'll be okay.
Re...Rei?! What are you doing here?!
ﾚ… ﾚｲ!? なんで ここに？
ｱﾝﾀ 成仏したんじゃ…｡
I thought you went to heaven.
(ﾚｲ)ちょいと
この世に未練ができちまってね｡
Well, I feel like I still have something to do in this world.
あぁ 心配いらないよ｡
But don't worry. The reason I came back here isn't because I was worried about you.
べつに 女将が心配で
戻ってきたんじゃない｡
背中を流してやりたい男が
できたのさ｡
It was because there's a man whose back I want to wash.
(笑い声)
(幽霊)すみません｡
Excuse me.
(お岩/ﾚｲ)
ようこそ 仙望郷の湯へ｡
Welcome to Senbokyo bathhouse.
Please do not cry
atop my grave.
For I am not there.
I am not asleep.
A thousand winds...
I've become a thousand winds
And now I'm blowing
across the great, big sky.
[Preview]
What? The next episode is about leveraging Gintama?
That sounds awfully familiar. What? No?
It's about leveraging Gintaman? That sounds even more familiar.
The next episode:
"Before Thinking About The Earth, Think About The More Endangered Gintaman's Future!"
[We did get ourselves purified, but we still had a few accidents this week as well.]
[Today's word of wisdom: Get yourselves purified as soon as possible!!]
[See you again next time!]